(Lishan Mountain)
(Lishan Academy)
Ye Li
has been ill since her return.
Life in the mountains
must have been hard.
On top of that,
she was supposed to marry Prince Li.
But with the swap,
she's marrying the disabled Prince Ding.
Lishan Academy may be a fine place,
but it's no match for the capital.
(Ye Li, daughter of second branch)
To think the peerless Prince Li
and the crippled Prince Ding
are holding weddings on the same day.
(Time loses meaning in the mountains.)
(The passing of years goes unnoticed.)
(Eight years have passed.)
(The good thing is,)
(I've returned.)
♪Memories hold you back
from fulfilling your dreams♪
♪Only by moving forward
can you find reunion♪
♪Endings only mark new routes♪
♪It's all part of the scenery♪
♪To the horizon's call♪
♪Your journey hasn't started♪
♪Towards mountains,
chase the stars bright♪
♪Let time embrace you
and wash away the past♪
♪Put every twist behind you♪
♪Drift leisurely through time♪
♪Make headway against the wind♪
♪Let mountains bow to your pace♪
♪Rush towards a life without regret♪
♪Let your nature burst free♪
=The First Jasmine=
=Episode 1=
My Lady.
My Lady, how are you feeling today?
Better.
I just picked up the medicine.
Xing, prepare the medicine for our lady.
With cold water or hot?
She's clueless. Give it to me.
Thank you, ma'am.
Come with me
to bring our lady her lunch.
When did it fly back?
It must be hungry.
Qingyu.
What was all the fuss about
at Yanru Pond?
(Qingyu, Xing)
Young Master accidentally fell in.
Everyone rushed over.
Fortunately, they got him out in time.
Right.
And I heard
the plaque bestowed by the late Emperor
was missing.
The one in the grand hall
that reads "Family of Charity".
That is missing?
It's terrible.
(Happiness)
Rong, are you hurt anywhere?
I-I'm scared.
Mom, hold me.
Come here, my child.
Master Wending, Elders,
when I came to clean at noon,
the plaque was there.
(Ye Wending, first branch)
Then Young Master fell into the pond.
So we hurried over to save him.
When we returned, the plaque was gone.
(Ye Wenhua, second branch)
It all happened within half an hour.
In half an hour?
How did such a huge plaque
vanish into thin air?
An inside job.
(Ye Wenshen, third branch)
An inside job for sure.
Since the thief
managed to infiltrate us,
why steal a plaque
instead of anything else?
Wending, isn't it obvious?
Someone is displeased with us,
thinking we don't deserve
the title "Family of Charity."
They're upholding justice
by taking this plaque back
for the late Emperor.
Just keep quiet.
Enough talk.
Our top priority now
is to locate the plaque.
How can we lose an imperial gift?
Wending, what is on your mind?
Think about it.
If someone tried to smuggle
such a huge plaque out,
it couldn't possibly go unnoticed.
Perhaps, the plaque
is hidden somewhere within the mansion.
Guards.
Master Wending.
Search the entire mansion.
Leave no stone unturned.
(Li Feibai)
Yes, Master.
(Ye Rong, young son of second branch)
(Ms. Wang,
subsequent wife of second branch)
Nothing here.
Over there.
Yes.
Nothing, Captain Li.
Search the Western Courtyard.
- Yes, Captain.
We need to inspect these chests.
You can't open them.
Step aside.
These are our lady's dowries.
You can't open them.
We're searching for a lost item
under command.
Open them.
- You can't.
- Wait.
My Lady.
You just took your medicine.
Why did you come out?
Something is missing.
I know you're just following orders.
But these
are the dowries my mom left for me.
I don't have the keys right now.
Forcing the chests open
might damage the items.
Who sent you?
Master Wending.
Take me to Uncle Wending.
(Rongxi Hall)
(Ye Ying,
second daughter of second branch)
My dear niece.
Didn't you ask to come here?
Speak your mind.
May you be well, Father.
It's been eight years.
You've lost so much weight.
Haven't you been back
for over two months?
You still haven't seen your father?
Father must have been too busy with work
to see me.
What a caring father
and a filial daughter.
I truly envy you.
Something is missing.
We must find it as soon as possible.
Li, show some understanding.
Uncle.
I know the bestowed plaque is missing.
I don't mean to stop you.
But these are the dowries
my mom left for me.
I don't have the keys.
All these years,
Mother has been keeping them for me.
Yes.
I have the keys.
Li's mom prepared these dowries
to take to the groom's family
on her wedding day.
Opening the chests early
would bring bad luck.
Bad luck?
If we don't find the plaque,
the entire Ye family
will be in grave trouble.
But that plaque is huge.
It won't fit inside a dowry chest.
Says who? I think it fits in this one.
Right, Li? Let's measure it.
(Duyou Zither)
This is the Duyou Zither,
three chi and five cun long.
It took Master Su seven years to craft.
The imperial plaque
is about four chi long.
The chest is big enough for that.
I told you it could fit.
Where's the key? Open it now.
Stop hesitating. The keys.
Wenhua.
Give them to her.
This is the Duyou Zither?
How can it be?
This zither looks like
that of a northerner.
Go ahead.
This is wrong. These are all wrong.
Father.
Do you truly detest me so deeply
that you have to take the dowries
my mom left for me?
Aren't you managing the household?
Tell us what's going on.
These are...
These are Ying's dowries.
I mixed them.
Li, you must believe me.
While you were away,
we never stopped thinking of you.
Especially your father.
He genuinely looked forward
to your return.
Really?
Of course.
We're keeping a close eye
on the dowry items
your mom left for you.
In the end,
you're the one
who knows how to pull tricks.
No wonder your maiden family
is prospering.
Look at my foolish wife.
You made us a laughingstock.
We found it.
Master Wending, Elders.
We found the plaque.
Where was it?
In the pond at the Western Courtyard.
Who put it there?
No idea yet.
Thankfully, Captain Li spotted
a corner of the plaque in the pond.
So we had it retrieved.
(Family of Charity)
Good sign.
Wending.
We found what we've lost.
Everything is fine.
Our "Family of Charity" plaque is found.
What a pity.
It's muddied by the filthy pond water.
Now it's "Family of Filth".
Wash it well
and hang it as soon as possible.
Yes, Master.
You may leave.
Thank goodness we found it.
Clean it well.
Especially "Charity".
Li,
we've found the plaque.
Why don't you go back and rest?
I made a mistake amidst the chaos
and almost mixed up
your dowries with Ying's.
Rest assured.
I'll sort them out and put them back.
You're right, Mother.
Luckily, we came across
the mistake today.
Otherwise,
wouldn't that make you
look like a thief one day?
Since Father, Uncles,
and the Elders are here today,
I'd like to discuss something with you.
My mom left a vast amount behind.
Farmlands, property deeds,
gold and silver shops,
antiques, jades, and such,
all exceedingly complex.
Thank you for managing these
on my behalf.
I won't trouble you with it
since I'm back.
Let's make the handover today.
Of course.
(Family of Charity)
I wanted to do it tomorrow,
but I'm worried that if we delay this,
those outsiders might accuse you
of withholding property
that isn't yours.
We can't let such accusations
tarnish your longstanding reputation.
So I should thank you, Li.
No need, Mother.
That would make us seem estranged.
I see you as my own daughter.
Both you and Ying are dear to me
in precisely the same way.
I promise I will be as filial as Ying
to repay your kindness.
My Lady, so many treasures.
You're rich.
This could last you forever.
You're exaggerating.
There will be plenty of uses for money.
Qingyu, have you checked everything?
Yes, My Lady.
Put them away.
Alright.
You must be tired.
Go rest.
- Yes, My Lady.
Our lady is formidable.
Yes, we'll have good days ahead of us.
Tao and Xing are still young.
They speak recklessly.
Please don't mind them.
You were younger than them
when you began serving me.
Qingshuang and I
returned to Lishan Mountain,
while you remained.
You've suffered a lot.
You must be tired, My Lady.
Get some rest.
I'll take my leave.
(Qingshuang)
My Lady, you must be so tired.
I'm fine.
Third watch, Zi hour.
(Ye Mansion)
Cold stars fill the sky.
Sleep peacefully. Don't startle.
(Mom, it's been eight years.)
(No one asked how you have been.)
Mom.
Why did you marry Father?
Because I fancied your father.
And did Father like you?
(Xu Wanzhou, Ye Wenhua's first wife)
Of course he did.
(Young Ye Li)
Your father likes me.
And he likes you too.
Tonight, they will send you
back to Lishan Mountain.
From now on,
we sever our ties
and go our separate ways.
Ye Li.
Call me "Elder Sister".
You had a nice victory today.
All thanks to your help.
Was the pond chilly?
My mom said
your husband-to-be is crippled.
Life won't be easy if you marry him.
Not necessarily.
Aren't you afraid I'll tell everyone?
Would you?
Your mom left you those dowries.
They're yours to begin with.
You can't get to me.
Says who?
(Ye Mansion)
(Master Zhu said)
(my mom was a fool.)
(What was so good about my father?)
(He was utterly worthless
apart from his good looks.)
My Lady.
The dowry chests are locked.
I'll have them moved out.
Come on in.
(Master Zhu was right.)
(My mom was a smart woman,)
(but when it came to men,)
(she had no taste.)
You look stunning.
My Lady.
Prince Ding sent the nuptial verses.
Let's go.
Congratulations.
Two weddings in one day.
That calls for celebration.
Congratulations, Madam.
You are blessed with profound fortune.
(Madam of the Ye family)
Wait...
Who is getting married?
Your granddaughters.
The brides are here.
Come here.
Look at the two brides.
Lady Ying looks stunning.
So pretty.
Lady Li is stunning too.
So beautiful.
- Grandmother.
What...?
Wanzhou.
I haven't seen you for a while.
Grandmother.
I am your mother-in-law.
How come you don't even recognize me?
Madam is tired.
I am...
Help Madam back to rest.
I am your mother-in-law.
I have been thinking of you.
Scatter gold and silver
to joy a newfound groom.
Beat the thieves, but greet the guests.
The sisters-in-law
have come to greet the bride.
Where do paired candles lead to?
Why does the goose crane its neck?
Brilliant light illuminates the path.
(Mo Jingli, Prince Li)
Ride gracefully
into the hall of splendor.
Why are we stuck here?
Where's the messenger we sent?
He should be back soon.
(Mo Wuyou, Prince Ding's nephew)
What if we miss the auspicious hour?
Ask them to step aside.
They can't block the road.
Right?
Just a second.
I'll report this to the master.
The bride proceeds from stately halls.
Scatter gold and silver
to joy a newfound groom.
Scatter gold and silver...
Make way, please.
Master Wenhua.
Both wedding processions have arrived.
Let's get started.
But Prince Li's wedding procession
blocked the alley,
making it inaccessible
for Prince Ding's procession.
Master Wenhua.
Prince Ding inquires about the plan.
Well...
Wenhua.
The auspicious hour has arrived.
Since Prince Li's carriage
is at the entrance,
I suggest
we let Ying set about first.
What about Li?
Wenhua, Li is also your daughter.
Don't tell me you agree with Wending.
No way.
Li will go first.
Lay the felt mat
to keep her feet off the ground.
It's not against custom.
You want Li to walk out by herself?
I've heard that fish beneath the ice
have to breach a crack open
to grasp a breath.
Li, you must remember
the dignity your father sees fit
to grant you today.
Nobody would think you're mute
if you stay quiet.
The auspicious hour is upon us.
The brides shall kneel in gratitude
for their parents' toil in raising them.
Honor and heed them.
Never disobey
your father- and mother-in-law.
- I won't forget your teachings.
Endeavor and revere.
Never transgress the proprieties
expected of a woman.
I won't forget your teachings.
The mother shall
adjust the bride's garments.
(The towering Lishan Mountain
rises into the sky.)
(The mighty Lishui River
flows broad and deep.)
(I traveled alone)
(when I left the capital back then,)
(and returned alone two months ago.)
(I could do it before.)
(I can do it again.)
Father.
I am leaving.
Chopsticks scattered. All ills undone.
Gate thrown wide. All blessings come.
(The late emperor)
(betrothed me to Prince Li.)
(I saw it as my way down the mountain.)
(But Prince Li broke his word.)
(He begged the Empress Dowager
for Ye Ying instead.)
(She agreed,)
(but then betrothed me to Prince Ding.)
(Her intentions remain unclear.)
(But regardless,)
(I'm off the mountain.)
(Qingbao)
(Suixin, Prince Li's Chief Clerk)
Chopsticks scattered. All ills undone.
Gate thrown wide. All blessings come.
Young Lord.
Aunt.
I am Mo Wuyou.
I am here on behalf of my uncle,
Prince Ding.
My uncle is unwell.
Therefore, we have omitted
some of the formalities.
I hope you will forgive us.
Please step into the carriage.
(Prince Ding's Mansion)
Mind your steps, dear bride.
Pass the felt mat.
(Prince Ding's Mansion)
Turn the mat to welcome offspring.
Pass the bag to start a line of heirs.
Grain and beans scattered once.
Ward off evil and disasters.
Grain and beans scattered twice.
Bring peace to the household.
(Wen Ran, Prince Ding's
eldest sister-in-law)
Ms. Wen, where is His Highness?
He mustn't be late.
He should be here soon.
Give him a second.
Will we miss the auspicious hour?
It has long since passed.
It's so late.
Will His Highness even come?
His Highness...
His Highness is detained
by pressing matters.
No matter what,
he should have arrived by now.
Could it be that
Prince Ding is displeased
with the Empress Dowager's
marriage arrangement?
That is not the case.
Go take a look.
Wait.
Where is His Highness?
In his study, I believe.
Let me fetch him in person.
Your Highness.
I am Prince Ding's steward.
My surname is Cui.
May I show you the way?
And that is...?
That is Director Lv Cheng
of the Bureau of Astronomy.
The Empress Dowager sent him
to aid His Highness' cultivation.
Your Highness, we must show respect.
Cultivation?
Stop there.
Who are you?
I am the Princess Consort.
(Lv Cheng,
Director of the Bureau of Astronomy)
Prince Ding is occupied
with urgent matters.
Am I not even allowed to see him?
(Day and Night Diligence)
(Mo Xiuyao, Prince Ding)
Your Highness.
My apologies. I will pick them up.
Copying sutras?
You have to do this
even on your wedding day?
What's wrong?
Nothing.
I think I finally understand my mom.
Mo Xiuyao, I am Ye Li.
I'm here to marry you.
It's our first meeting.
Let me treat you to a dessert.
No?
Well then, let's go.
Where to?
To the wedding.
Today is our wedding day.
Are you going to
keep copying sutras here?
But I haven't finished yet.
Then do it later.
I will help you once we're back.
Let's go.
Where are you going, Your Highness?
Isn't it obvious?
He hasn't completed
his assignment today.
Getting married
is one of life's biggest events.
Does an assignment matter more?
Your Highness, you may not know.
The Bureau of Astronomy reported
that the excessive bloodshed
in this mansion
has offended the deities.
His Highness's unhealing leg ailment,
Ms. Wen's chronic illness,
and Young Lord's incorrigible behavior.
These are divine punishments.
Out of compassion,
the Empress Dowager
ordered me to divine a remedy.
Only if the head of the household
copies the sutras and recites them daily
can this calamity be resolved.
Does he have to do it now?
Can't we rearrange?
I'm only following Her Majesty's order.
I don't make rearrangements.
I see.
Steward Cui.
Here.
Prepare the carriage.
I'm returning to Lishan Mountain.
What do you mean by this?
By the Empress Dowager's decree,
I came to marry Prince Ding.
But the auspicious hour has passed.
You still refuse to let him go.
It seems the wedding won't proceed.
In that case,
why would I stay here?
I'd better head back.
But I'm afraid you will have to
go to the Anqing Palace
for further instructions.
I'm merely carrying out orders.
I understand.
You've worked hard, Lord Lv.
Steward Cui.
Here.
Let's go.
You're Ye Li?
Yes.
You're from Lishan Academy?
I heard you were
betrothed to Prince Li.
You are very well-informed.
Prince Li is handsome
and gentle-mannered,
with exceptional skills in the arts.
He's the ideal husband
for the noble ladies in the capital.
But I sit in a wheelchair
due to my impaired legs.
My family carries the burden
of past crimes.
Its glory has faded.
You've gone from Prince Li's bride
to my wife.
How do you feel?
Prince Li has become so popular now?
No wonder he broke it off.
I didn't know
because I had been in seclusion.
But Your Highness,
your family may have lost its splendor.
The Lishan Academy
is a fading glory too.
Our marriage is like
withered lotuses beside dead willows
and dying grass under winter crows.
A perfect match.
Let's not point any fingers.
The auspicious hour has passed.
We should hurry up.
Ms. Wen, they are here.
Xiuyao.
Sorry, we're late.
No problem. I'm glad you made it.
Your Highness,
it's time for the ceremony.
Bow to the mirror.
Henceforth united as one
before the mirror.
Shared devotion
dispels all hidden evils.
Bind the sash and adjust the attire.
Hold the red silk
and enter the bridal chamber.
Are you hungry, Your Highness?
Want to eat something?
Or have some wine?
What is that?
Curious?
The wedding night
is much easier for common folks.
The natural bond
between man and woman comes easily.
But an impaired man needs some help
on the wedding night.
Want to try it?
These are the dowries
my mom left for me.
What are you doing?
I want to find you a gift.
A gift?
Why?
Because I'm grateful.
As you know,
I was betrothed to Prince Li.
I thought he would marry me
when the time came,
and I would leave the mountain.
But he broke off the engagement.
I understand.
Nowadays, no one wants anything
to do with Lishan.
But you're willing to marry me
and get me off the mountain.
So I'm grateful.
Come here.
Your Highness, what's wrong?
Are you hurting?
Your Highness?
Scared?
Jin.
Here.
People from Lishan Academy
are said to be clever.
But Ye Li.
Rein in your cleverness.
This place is no haven.
And I'm not interested in this marriage.
If you wish,
we could leave each other in peace.
If not,
wait a year or so,
and I'll grant you a divorce.
We can part ways peacefully. Agreed?
(Tuisi Pavilion)
(Preview)
(Mo Xiuyao.)
(What my mom owes your family,)
(I'll pay on her behalf.)
As you know,
the family has received
divine punishments.
I heard you are from the south.
How long have you been here?
Three years.
Let me read your fortune.
Mo Xiuyao, do you want to have a try?
Please leave, Ye Li.
I don't need you.
I've mastered it too.
Is it similar?
♪Memories hold you back
from fulfilling your dreams♪
♪Only by moving forward
can you find reunion♪
♪Endings only mark new routes♪
♪It's all part of the scenery♪
♪To the horizon's call♪
♪Your journey hasn't started♪
♪Towards mountains,
chase the stars bright♪
♪Both joy and grief
make the trip worthwhile♪
♪Trying to catch up
to your own lost shadow♪
♪Within the wilds, echoes thrive♪
♪Clear mind leads to a clear path♪
♪Be grateful to your losses♪
♪Make your steps weightless♪
♪Towards mountains,
chase the stars bright♪
♪Let time embrace you
and wash away the past♪
♪Put every twist behind you,
drift leisurely through time♪
♪Make headway against the wind,
let mountains bow to your pace♪
♪Rush towards a life without regret♪
♪Let your nature burst free♪
♪Unbound by form♪